Narayana Manjunath Reddy

Bangalore | nmanjunath@live.com | +91 8904836330 | manjunathnreddy.github.io/nfc/

SUMMARY

Senior developer with 8+ years in C++ and Python, 3+ years in ML, and 3 years as a team lead. Proficient in design patterns, data structures, multithreading and Agile development. Strong communicator, collaborative and fast learner.

SKILLS

Languages: C++, Python, R, Rust, SQL

Libraries: Boost, Qt, PyTorch, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Plotly, XGBoost, Spacy, Tidyverse, Shiny

Tools: Cmake, Git, JIRA

EDUCATION

Technische Universität Kaiserslautern, Germany

Oct 2022

- Masters in Computer Science(Intelligent Systems)
- Thesis: A contrastive framework for text style embeddings
- Coursework: Data Science, Deep Learning, Machine Learning, Regression & Time series

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Cerence – Aachen, Germany

Aug 2023 - Sep 2024

- Tech & Tools: Windows & Linux, Bash, C++, Python, SQL, PyTorch, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Git, JIRA
- Enhanced audio recognition in ASR by extending support for dynamic audio recognition configuration
- Simplified syncing of nested repositories and took ownership of custom version control system
- Integrated Generative NLP model into existing Audio Recognition System

Senior Software Development Engineer, Amadeus – Aachen, Germany

Oct 2022 - Apr 2023

- Tech & Tools: Windows, C++, Python, Cython, Numpy, Git, JIRA
- Created fail-safe using geocodes and REST calls, saving 30 minutes per faulty booking
- Scaled up data import resulting in 60% faster completion of data production

Scientific Assistant, Fraunhofer ITWM – Kaiserslautern, Germany

Sep 2020 - Sep 2022

- Tech & Tools: Windows, R, Python, PyTorch, Plotly, XGBoost, Spacy, Tidyverse, Shiny, SQL, Pandas, Git, JIRA
- Anonymized over 1500 e-mail transcripts of the client's customer service issues with various NLP techniques
- Improved ML ensemble to detect fraud from 65% to 72% and created dashboard to visualize results

Student Assistant, DFKI - Kaiserslautern, Germany

Feb 2020 - Feb 2021

- Tech & Tools: Windows, C++, Qt, OpenCV, Git, JIRA
- Improved lookup algorithm from $\mathcal{O}(n)$ to $\mathcal{O}(\log n)$ in video synchronizer for eye contact visualization

Senior Engineer, Bosch – Bangalore, India

Aug 2015 - Jul 2018

- Tech & Tools: Windows & Linux, Bash, C++, SQL, Qt, CMake, Boost, Python, OpenCV, Git, JIRA
- Led the development of a navigational application, as Scrum Master and Tech Lead
- Reduced loading time of the application by 80% and memory footprint by 10%
- Created an automatic visual testing tool, saving 4 hours of manual testing per month

Application Developer, IBM – Kolkata, India

Sep 2012 - Aug 2015

- Tech & Tools: Windows & Linux, Bash, C++, SQL, Python, Rational ClearCase, Rational TeamConcert
- Independently designed and developed new application features
- Automated generation of project-specific boilerplate code saving the team 1 hour per month
- Tracked and communicated the development progress as Scrum Master of the team